<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Occasionally clever</title>
    <link>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Series on Occasionally clever</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Universal reservoir: sampling a fixed number of elements from unbounded data</title>
      <link>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/universal-reservoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/universal-reservoir/</guid>
      <description>Reservoir sampling is the process of sampling a fixed number of elements from unbounded data. Universal hash functions provide an efficient, deterministic, and infinitely scalable approach to the reservoir that is easy to implement in any data environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A visualization trick obvious in hindsight</title>
      <link>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/visualization-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/visualization-trick/</guid>
      <description>Data visualization is a key part of every data science and machine learning project. It can be difficult given that we usually have more points to draw than space on screen. Most of us realize pretty quickly that we can summarize data for certain visualizations, the most common being the histogram. What took me an embarrassingly long time to realize is that scatterplots can be easily handled by its generalization: the nd-histogram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping in SQL; or, getting s--- done with the tools you have</title>
      <link>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/bootstrapping-in-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/bootstrapping-in-sql/</guid>
      <description>SQL is the lingua franca of data platforms. It is many things, but a statistical language is not one of them. In this post, I&#39;ll cover an approach to bootstrap when it&#39;s your best, or only, option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal bootstrap: a superpower</title>
      <link>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/universal-bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/universal-bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>Bootstrapping is commonly used in computational statistics and machine learning for uncertainty quantification, hypothesis testing, and ensembling. By combining universal sampling with Poisson bootstrap, I show how the universal bootstrap unlocks incredibly sophisticated analysis at any scale in any tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal sampling: better sampling for a better tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/universal-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ptrcknchlsn.xyz/posts/universal-sampling/</guid>
      <description>Universal hash functions efficiently and deterministically map arbitrary input to uniformly distributed integers. In this post, I demonstrate how to leverage these functions for sampling from datasets and distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>